MENU 

Search 

Privacy Policy
==============

Academy of Dental Learning & OSHA Training
------------------------------------------

### Privacy, Security, and Technology Policy

**The Academy of Dental Learning & OSHA Training (ADL)** is committed to the free flow of information that can help consumers make good marketplace decisions. It is also committed to promoting and protecting the privacy rights of individuals, as enumerated in various state and federal statutes. It is our policy to limit the collection and safeguard the privacy of personal information collected or maintained by ADL.

We follow these principles in collecting and managing personal information:

**We collect personal information on individuals only as allowed by law.** We limit the collection of personal information to what is relevant and necessary to accomplish a lawful purpose. For example, we need to know someone's address, telephone number, license number and state of licensure, among other things, to properly identify the person before issuing a CE certificate.

We do not collect home, business or e-mail addresses, or account information from persons who browse our Internet sites. We collect personal information about you only if you provide it to us voluntarily through e-mail, registration forms, or surveys.

We use demographic information, if you respond voluntarily to our surveys or other interactive communications, we collect the responses and use the information to improve the quality and range of ADL products and services.

We use personal information only for the specified purposes, or purposes consistent with those purposes, unless we get the consent of the subject of the information, or unless required by law or regulation.

**We use information security safeguards.** We take reasonable industry precautions, including off-site storage of data, to protect the personal information on individuals collected or maintained by ADL against loss, unauthorized access, and illegal use or disclosure. Personal information is stored in secure locations. Our staff is trained on procedures for the release of information, and access to personal information is limited to those staff whose work requires it.

ADL strictly protects the security of your personal information. We carefully protect your data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction.  To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity, such as password and username, before granting access to your data.

Your personal information is never shared outside the company without your permission, except under conditions explained above. Inside the company, data is stored in password-controlled servers with limited access.

You also have a significant role in protecting your information. No one can see or edit your personal information without knowing your username and password, so do not share these with others.

**We use SSL encryption** when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card and personal information. Credit card numbers are only used for processing payment and are not used for other purposes. Our efforts to protect credit card fraud help protect your financial data security. As part of real-time payment processing, ADL subscribes to a fraud management service via our merchant credit card processor. This service gives both you and ADL an extra level of protection to guard against credit card fraud.

ADL has implemented security features in our database to protect your personal information from unauthorized access. We maintain our servers in a controlled, secured environment. Only staff who need to have access to your personal information in order to perform their job function are authorized to access the database. Constant changes to the internet and technology mean that we cannot guarantee that data transmission will be 100% secure, or safe from attack by unauthorized intruders.

### More Credit Card Security/ Merchant Services Information

**We use PayPal as our credit card processor.**  All your financial information (like your credit card number) is securely stored and encrypted on PayPal servers, so you don’t need to share your financial information with the person you’re buying from.  
  
In addition, PayPal transactions are monitored 24 hours a day, seven days a week, by a dedicated team of security specialists. Their mission is to identify suspicious activity and help protect you from fraudulent transactions.

### The HostGator Network – State of the Art Technology for Your Protection

**We use HostGator Network to manage primary data** and who provides network provider services for our company and for out customers’ protection.

HostGator has partnered with SoftLayer for all primary data center and network-provider services. HostGator's long standing relationship with SoftLayer allows HostGator's customers to utilize one of the world's best networks to power their web sites and ensure maximum uptime. SoftLayer's world-class datacenters feature state of the art security, power, safety, and cooling systems - all designed to ensure that service remains uninterrupted.

### Data Center Features

HostGator houses servers in multiple SoftLayer datacenters. Ranging from 22,000 to more than 78,000 square feet, these world-class datacenters contain industry-standard technology to ensure that all servers stay cool, secure, and on-line at all times. The datacenters feature redundant power, HVAC, and fire detection/suppression systems, and are monitored 24/7/365 by both HostGator and SoftLayer's Network Operation Centers.

**We will provide additional explanations of our privacy policy if requested**. If you have further questions about our privacy policy, you may write or call the Academy of Dental Learning & OSHA Training, PO Box 14585, Albany, NY 12212. Phone: 1 (800) 522-1207.

Copyright © 2024. Academy of Dental Learning and OSHA Training, LLC. All rights reserved.
